Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2 5583/2
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 2
0000-2999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
5583/2
74 cubic feet
74 linear ft.
Records (documents), publications (documents).
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations.
5697820
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
M. Clark, July 13, 2016
EAD encoding:
Elizabeth Parker, April 24, 2023
Scope and Contents
Publications, manuals, policies, and plans issued by a large sample of Fortune 500 corporations and by a variety of organizations, such as professional and trade associations, government agencies, and educational and cultural organizations. The materials issued by corporations include company histories, employee newsletters, employee benefit plans, personnel practice manuals, performance appraisal forms, affirmative action policies, training brochures, job descriptions, and career development programs as well as national trade association documents and recruitment material.
Several economic activities(sectors) are represented in the collection, such as manufacturing, transportation, mining, banking, insurance, utilities, trade, and services. Corporations whose pamphlets are held in the collection include AT&T, Bethlehem Steel, Bell Telephone System, Firestone Tire & Rubber, Ford Motor Co., General Electric, General Foods, General Mills, General Motors, Goodyear Tire & Rubber, Heinz, International Harvester, Johnson & Johnson, Lockheed Aircraft Co., Maytag Co., Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., National Association of Manufacturers, Pennsylvania Railroad Co., Radio Corporation of America (RCA), Standard Oil, Tennessee Valley Authority, Union Carbide, and Westinghouse Electric among numerous other corporations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5880: Archives Organization File V, Additional Company Documents 5583/1: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 1 5583/3: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 3 5583/4: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 4. Corporate and Organizational Publications 5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5 5583/6: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 6 5956: Archives Organization File Additional records
Adult education; Aeronautics; Agricultural industries; Aluminum industry and trade; Airlines; Aircraft industry; Agricultural machinery; Architectural metal-work; Automobile industry and trade; Arbitration, Industrial; Agricultural chemicals industry; Audio equipment industry; Bituminous materials industry; Building trades; Buildings--Environmental engineering; Banks and banking; Breweries; Baked products industry; Business consultants; Clothing trade; Coal mines and mining; Chemical industry; Compressor industry; Clerks (Retail trade); Computer industry; Cereal products; Consumer Protection; Container industry; Credit Unions; Clay industries; Cement industries; Copper alloys; Dairy products industry; Detergent industry; Executives--Training of; Electric power transmission; Electronics industries; Food industry and trade; Frozen foods and industry; Footwear industry; Fruit trade; Farm produce--Marketing--Government policy; Finance, Public; Glass container industry; Glass manufacture; Gas extraction; Grain trade; Grocery trade; Gasket industry; Human capital; Hydroelectric power plants; Life insurance.; Iron industry and trade; Property insurance.; Casualty insurance.; Instructional materials industry; Health insurance.; Investment banking; Infant formula industry; Knit good industry; Labor unions; Local transit; Luggage industry; Logging; Medical supplies industry; Medicaid; Motor vehicle industry; Metal trade; Meat industry and trade; Military vehicle industry; Medical instruments and apparatus industry; Management; Measuring instruments; Natural gas pipelines; Notions (Merchandise); Newspaper publishing; Navigation equipment industry; National security; Office management; Office equipment and supplies; Petroleum refineries; Photographic industry; Paper folding (Graphic design); Public utilities; Paper products industry; Political participation; Plastics industry and trade; Pharmaceutical industry; Paint industry and trade; Public administration; Public opinion polls; Paper bag industry; Retail trade; Rug and carpet industry; Railroads; Rubber industry and trade; Railroad equipment industry; Roller bearings; Security systems industry; Service industries; Social security; Shipment of goods; Sanitary supply industry; Soybean industry; Slaughtering and slaughter-houses; Transportation equipment industry.; Telecommunication.; Trucking industry.; Trucks--Design and construction.; Textile industry.; Trade associations.; Tobacco industry.; Universities and colleges.; Vocational education.; Wood products.; Welding equipment industry.; Woolen goods industry.; A. Kimball Company.; B.F. Goodrich Company.; Civil Service Commission of the City of New York.; Council of Retail Merchants (Ohio); Eli Lilly and Company.; General Electric Company. Erie Works (Erie, PA).; General Electric Company. River Works (Lynn, Mass.); General Electric Company. Pittsfield Works (Pittsfield, Mass.); General Foods Corporation.; General Mills, inc.; General Motors Corporation.; General Motors Corporation. Delco Products Division.; General Petroleum Corporation.; General Shoe Corporation.; General Telephone & Electronics Corporation.; General Telephone Company of California.; General Telephone Company of Indiana.; General Telephone Company of Michigan.; General Telephone Corporation.; Geneva Steel (Firm); Gerber Products Company.; Glass Container Manufacturers Institute.; Glenshaw Glass Company.; Globe Ticket Company.; B.F. Goodrich Company.; Goodyear Atomic Corporation.; Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company.; Grand Union Company.; Graphic Arts Employers of America.; Grumman Aircraft Engineering Corporation.; Guaranty Trust Company of New York.; H.J. Heinz Company.; Hallmark Cards, Inc.; Haloid Company.; Haloid Xerox, Inc.; Harris Trust and Savings Bank.; Harris-Intertype Corp.; Harris-Seybold Company.; Harvard University.; Hawaii Employers Council.; Hawaiian Pineapple Co.; Hercules Incorporated.; Honeywell Inc.; Hotpoint.; University of Hawaii (Honolulu). -- Industrial Relations Center.; Illinois Bell Telephone Company.; Illinois Central Industries.; Illinois Central Railroad Company.; University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign. -- Institute of Labor and Industrial Relations.; Imperial Chemical Industries, ltd.; Imperial Oil Limited.; Industrial Accident Prevention Associations.; Industrial Association of San Francisco.; Industrial Hygiene Council.; Industrial Hygiene Foundation of America.; Ingersoll-Rand Company.; Inland Steel Company.; Institute of Life Insurance (New York, N.Y.); Institute of Management & Labor Relations.; International Business Machines Corporation.; International Nickel Company.; International Paper Company.; John Hancock Mutual Life Insurance Company.; Johns-Manville Corporation.; Johnson & Johnson.; Johnson Wax.; Jones & Laughlin Steel Corporation.; Kaiser Steel Corporation.; Kennecott Copper Corporation.; Kimberly-Clark Corporation.; Koppers Company.; Kroger Company.; Leeds and Northrup Company.; Lever Brothers Company.; Libby, McNeill & Libby.; Libby-Owens Company.; Libby-Owens-Ford Glass Company.; Liberty Mutual Insurance Company.; Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company.; Lincoln Electric Company.; Lincoln Telephone & Telegraph Company.; Lockheed Aircraft Corporation.; Lukens Steel Company.; Lumberman's Industrial Relations Committee.; Manufacturers Hanover Trust Company.; Marathon Corporation.; Marathon Oil Company.; Marquette Cement Manufacturing Company.; Marquette University.; Marshall Field & Company.; Maytag Corporation.; McCord Corporation.; McGraw-Hill Book Company.; McGraw-Hill Companies.; McGraw-Hill Publishing Company.; McKesson and Robbins, inc.; McMurray Company.; Mead Corporation.; Mead Johnson & Company.; Merchants and Manufacturers Association.; Merck & Co.; Meredith Publishing Group.; Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner & Beane.; Mesta Machine Company.; Metropolitan Life Insurance Company.; Michigan Bell Telephone Company.; Michigan Central Railroad Company.; Michigan. Civil Rights Commission.; Michigan. Civil Service Commission.; Michigan. Department of Labor.; Michigan. Department of Social Services.; Michigan. Labor Mediation Board.; Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Company.; Mobil Chemical Company.; Mobil Oil Corporation.; Mobil Overseas Oil Company.; Mobil Research and Development Corporation.; Mohawk Airlines.; Monroe Calculation Machine Company.; Monsanto Chemical Company.; Montgomery Ward.; Motorola, inc.; Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York.; Nash-Kelvinator Corporation.; National Academy of Arbitrators.; National Association of Broadcasters.; National Association of Foremen.; National Association of Furniture Manufacturers.; National Association of Manufacturers (U.S.); National Biscuit Company.; National Broadcasting Company.; National Cash Register Company.; National Coal Association.; National Committee for Full Employment (U.S.); National Consumers' League.; National Council on the Aging.; National Education Association of the United States; National Electrical Manufacturers Association.; National Farmers' Union (U.S.); National Foremen's Institute.; National Industrial Council (U.S.); National Management Association (U.S.); National Metal Trades Association (U.S.); National Restaurant Association (U.S.); National Restaurant Managers Association (U.S.); National Safety Council; National Society of Professional Engineers.; National Steel Corporation.; National Urban League.; New England Electric System.; New England Powers Association.; New England Telephone and Telegraph Company.; New Jersey Bell Telephone Company.; New Jersey Manufacturers Association.; New Jersey. Department of Civil Service.; New York (N.Y.). Department of Personnel.; New York (State). Temporary Commission Against Discrimination.; New York (State). Department of Civil Service.; New York (State). Department of Labor.; New York (State). Public Employment Relations Board.; New York (State). Workmen's Compensation Board.; New York Central Railroad Company.; New York Shipping Association.; New York State Electric and Gas Corporation.; New York Stock Exchange.; New York Telephone Company.; New York Times Company.; North American Aviation, inc.; Northeastern University (Boston, Mass.); Northwest Packers and Growers, inc.; Northwestern Bell Telephone Company.; Nunn-Bush Shoe Company.; Ohio Oil Company.; Ontario Hydro.; Organization Resources Counselors, Inc.; Owens-Corning Fiberglas Corporation.; Owens-Illinois Glass Company.; P.H. Hanes, Knitting Company.; Pacific Gas and Electric Company.; Pacific Power and Light Company.; Penn Central Merger Information Committee.; Penn Central Transportation Company.; Pennsylvania Railroad.; Peoples Gas Light and Coke Company.; Personnel Management Association of New York.; Personnel Management Association of the Northeast.; Personnel Management Association, inc.; Pfizer Inc.; Philadelphia Gas Works.; Philadelphia Rapid Transit Company.; Philadelphia Transportation Company.; Philip Morris and Company.; Phillips Petroleum Company.; Pillsbury Mills, Inc.; Pitney-Bowes, inc.; Pittsburgh Plate Glass Company.; Port of New York Authority.; Potomac Electric Power Company.; Potomac Sand & Gravel.; Procter & Gamble Company.; Prudential Insurance Company of America.; Public Personnel Association.; Public Service Corporation of New Jersey.; Public Service Electric and Gas Company.; State University of New York.; Theo. Hamm Brewing Company.; Thomas Macy & Co.; University of Michigan.; University of Minnesota.; University of Minnesota. Industrial Relations Center.; University of Mississippi.
5697820
- Box: 24, folder: 1 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Agreement, Publication (Box 24, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    July 21. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: D & H Anthracite, Publication (Box 24, Folder 2)
    Item is in English.
  - Item 2: The Production and Preparation of Anthracite, Publication (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Hudson Triangle, Publication (Box 24, Folder 3)
    December. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Principles Governing Working Relationships Between The Hudson Motor Car Company And Hudson Supervision, Publication (Box 24, Folder 4)
    October 6. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Principles Governing Working Relationships Between The Hudson Motor Car Company And Hudson Supervision, Publication (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: Principles Governing Working Relationships Between The Hudson Motor Car Company And Hudson Supervision, Publication (Box 24, Folder 4)
    October 18. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: The Hudson Motor-Salaried Insurance Plan, Publication (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: The Hudson Motor-UAW-CIO Insurance Plan For Hourly Rated Employees, Publication (Box 24, Folder 6)
    January 16. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Supervisory Handbook, Publication (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Employees Hand Book, Publication (Box 24, Folder 8)
    July 1, June 30. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Labor Agreement Between The Hudson Pulp & Paper Corp. And Unitd Papermakers & Paperworkers, Publication (Box 24, Folder 8)
    June 1. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Contract Between The Independent Metal Workers Union Local 1 and 2, Publication (Box 24, Folder 9)
    August 1. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Report to the Department of Labor, Publication (Box 24, Folder 10)
    October 17. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Collective Bargaining Agreement, Publication (Box 24, Folder 11)
    March 1. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: What Oil Means to Texas, Publication (Box 24, Folder 11)
    By Richard J. Gonzalez. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: A brief look at Humble Oil & Refining Company, Publication (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Item 4: Our Last, Best Hope, Publication (Box 24, Folder 11)
    By Hines H. Baker. November. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Our Greatest Asset, Publication (Box 24, Folder 11)
    By Hines H. Baker. May 1. Item is in English.
  - Item 6: Milestones In The Growth Of Humble, Publication (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Item 7: Humble Oil & Refining Company Management Organization Chart, Publication (Box 24, Folder 11)
    November. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: What Makes America Great?, Publication (Box 24, Folder 11)
    By Richard J. Gonzalez. May 9. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Tax Policy and Petroleum Supplies, Publication (Box 24, Folder 11)
    By Hines H. Baker. November 15. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Humble and you, Publication (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Item 2: How To Recruit, Interview and Hire Field Personnel, Publication (Box 24, Folder 12)
    October. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: How Humble Oil Encourages Employees To Participate In Politics, Publication (Box 24, Folder 12)
    March. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Working With Humble, Publication (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Item 5: Looking at Humble, Publication (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Item 6: Qualification Record, Publication (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Item 7: Careers In Energy, Publication (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Item 8: The Most Valuable Fuel, Publication (Box 24, Folder 12)
    By Chas F. Jones. September 22. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Humble Oil & Refining Company Management Organization Chart, Publication (Box 24, Folder 13)
    May. Item is in English.
  - Item 2: Humble Oil & Refining Company Operating Territories, Publication (Box 24, Folder 13)
    August. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Humble Oil & Refining Company Management Organization Chart, Publication (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Item 4: "High Spots" Of The Humble Annuity & Thrift Plan for Employees of the Humble Oil & Refining Company and Its Participating Affiliates, Publication (Box 24, Folder 13)
    January 1. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: For Houston Office Employees of Humble Oil & Refining Company and Humble Pipe Line Company, Publication (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Item 6: educational refund policy, Publication (Box 24, Folder 13)
    May 1. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Hospitalization and Surgical Benefits Insurance Plan of Humble Oil & Refining Company, Publication (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Item 2: Text of Humble Benefit Plan, Publication (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Item 3: A Guide to Your Employee Benefits, Publication (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Item 4: Humble Oil & Refining Company a guide to your Employee Benefits, Publication (Box 24, Folder 14)
    January. Item is in English.
  - Item 5: Highlights of The Employee Benefit Program Humble For the information of employees covered by the Humble Benefit Plan, Publication (Box 24, Folder 14)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Section I-E History And Organization Of Humble Oil & Refining Company, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 2: Informative Talks About Humble, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 3: Safety manual Production Department, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 4: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 5: Safety Information can keep the Spring in your step!, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 6: American Engineer, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 7: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
    April. Item is in English.
  - Item 8: Coin Your Ideas System, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 9: Supervisor's Guide To His Role In The Coin Your Ideas System, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 10: Better Skills for Better Jobs, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 11: Humble Oilways, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 12: Motion Pictures In Color, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 13: Humble's Earn and Learn Program Teaches Stenographic and Office Skills, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 14: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 15: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 16: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 17: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
    February. Item is in English.
  - Item 18: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 19: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 20: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 21: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 22: Private Enterprise And The Great Society, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
    By M. A. Wright. September. Item is in English.
  - Item 23: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 24: BayTown Refinery Information And Opinion Survey, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 25: Employee Relations Department, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 26: Taxation of Petroleum, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
    By Richard J. Gonzalez. June 12. Item is in English.
  - Item 27: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 28: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 29: Baytown Briefs, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
    November 9. Item is in English.
  - Item 30: The Humble Extra, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 31: The Humble Way, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
    Fall. Item is in English.
  - Item 32: 1958 Humble Oil & Refining Company Annual Report, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 33: 1952 Annual Report Humble Oil & Refining Company, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 34: The Humble Bee, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 35: Humble Esso Enjay, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 36: Welcome to Humble, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 37: The Humble Bee, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 38: Humble Today, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Item 39: Humble News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 15)
    July. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Regulations of The Employees' Benefit Department, Publication (Box 24, Folder 16)
    July 1. Item is in English.
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Staff News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 2: ontario hydro news release, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
    April 27. Item is in English.
  - Item 3: Announce New Manager Of Niagara Region, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 4: Water Power And Its Development, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 5: Ontario Hydro 1963, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 6: Ontario Hydro 16mm. Film Catalogue, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 7: A Guidebook On Public Relations, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 8: Hydroscope, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
    May 21. Item is in English.
  - Item 9: Hydro Golden Jubilee, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 10: Ontario Hydro News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 11: Ontario Hydro Staff News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 12: Ontario Hydro 1955, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 13: Ontario Hydro Staff News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 14: Ontario Hydro News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 15: Ontario Hydro News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 16: Ontario Hydro Staff news, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Item 17: Ontario Hydro News, Publication (Box 24, Folder 17)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: An Introduction To Ontario Hydro, Publication (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Item 2: EHV Superhighway of Power, Publication (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Item 3: Brief To The Committee On The Organization Of Government In Ontario, Publication (Box 24, Folder 18)
    By James S. Duncan. November 18. Item is in English.
  - Item 4: Power From Niagara, Publication (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Item 5: Kilowatts From Coal, Publication (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Item 6: Douglas Point Nuclear Power Station, Publication (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Item 7: Lakeview Generating Station, Publication (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Item 8: Richard L. Hearn Generating Station, Publication (Box 24, Folder 18)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Directive, Publication (Box 24, Folder 19)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: ICI Sales In 1974 Exceed $7 Billion; Earnings Increase 46%, Publication (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Item 2: ICI Magazine, Publication (Box 24, Folder 20)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Faculty and Staff Handbook, Publication (Box 24, Folder 21)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: The Telephone Company, Publication (Box 24, Folder 22)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: Something Extra, Publication (Box 24, Folder 23)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: Centennial Report the financial story of the first hundred years Illinois Central Railroad For 100 Years-the Main Line of Mid-America, Publication (Box 24, Folder 24)
- Box: 24, folder: (Box 24, Folder 25)